Mostly all new jokes.
Naked Gun 33⅓: The Final Insult is a comedy, crime film directed by Peter Segal.
Frank Drebin is persuaded out of retirement to go undercover in a state prison.
There he has to find out what top terrorist, Rocco,
has planned for when he escapes.
Adding to his problems, Frank's wife, Jane, is desperate for a baby.
Lt. Frank Drebin, played by Leslie Nielsen.
Jane Spencer, played by Priscilla Presley.
Ed Hocken, played by George Kennedy.
Nordberg, played by O. J. Simpson.
Rocco, played by Fred Ward.
Muriel, played by Kathleen Freeman.
Naked Gun 33⅓: The Final Insult is a 1994 American crime comedy film directed by Peter Segal (in
his directorial debut) and written by Pat Proft, David Zucker and Robert LoCash.
The film is the third installment in the Naked Gun film series,
which was based on the television series, Police Squad!
It is the sequel to The Naked Gun: From the Files of Police Squad!
(1988) and The Naked Gun 2½: The Smell of Fear (1991).
The Final Insult is the first film in the series that is not directed by David
Zucker, with him serving as producer and co-writer instead.
Police Squad!
co-creators Jim Abrahams and Jerry Zucker returned as executive producers.
The "33⅓" in the title is a reference to the number of
rotations per minute at which phonograph records play.
Leslie Nielsen returns as Lieutenant Frank Drebin (his original character from
Police Squad!), along with Priscilla Presley as Jane Spencer Drebin, O.
Simpson (in his last feature film before his arrest on murder charges three months
later) as Officer Nordberg, and George Kennedy as Captain Ed Hocken.
Newcomers to the series Fred Ward, Anna Nicole Smith, and Kathleen Freeman co-star
as a gang of bombers set to blow up the Academy Awards ceremony.
Raye Birk reprises his role as Pahpshmir from The Naked
Gun: From the Files of Police Squad!
This was the last Naked Gun film to have any involvement by Zucker,
Abrahams and Zucker before Abrahams' death in 2024.
The film explores themes of police, undercover,
parody, sexual humor, slapstick comedy.
The tone is lighthearted.